Mystery runs in the family.
Enola Holmes is a adventure, mystery, crime film directed by Harry Bradbeer.
While searching for her missing mother, intrepid teen Enola Holmes uses her
sleuthing skills to outsmart big brother Sherlock and help a runaway lord.
Enola Holmes, played by Millie Bobby Brown.
Sherlock Holmes, played by Henry Cavill.
Mycroft Holmes, played by Sam Claflin.
Eudoria Holmes, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Lord Tewkesbury, played by Louis Partridge.
Lestrade, played by Adeel Akhtar.
Enola Holmes is a 2020 mystery film starring Millie Bobby Brown as the title character, the teenage sister of the already famous
Victorian-era detective Sherlock Holmes (portrayed by Henry Cavill) and Mycroft Holmes (portrayed by Sam Claflin).
The film is directed by Harry Bradbeer from a screenplay by Jack Thorne that adapts
the first novel in The Enola Holmes Mysteries series by Nancy Springer.
In the film, Enola travels to London to find her missing mother (portrayed by Helena Bonham Carter) but ends up on a thrilling
adventure, pairing up with a runaway lord as they attempt to solve a mystery that threatens the entire country.
Filming began in July 2019.
Originally planned for a cinematic release by Warner Bros.
Pictures, the distribution rights to the film were picked
up by Netflix due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
Enola Holmes was released on September 23, 2020.
The film received positive reviews from critics,
who praised Brown's performance.
It became one of the most-watched original Netflix film releases, with an estimated
76 million households watching the film over its first four weeks.
A sequel, Enola Holmes 2, was released on Netflix on November 4, 2022.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, detective,
child prodigy, victorian england, female protagonist.
The tone is mind_bending.